Drew Johnston

Software Architect and Engineer

Motivation

I love to create solutions that simplify complex and interesting business problems to make everyone's life easier. Most of my 18 years of experience is in creating custom backend solutions. I'm interested in experiences that can take full advantage of my development team management, as well as my extensive application development experience and skill-set, to allow me to continue to grow.



Qualifications

- Self-motivated, knowledgeable, experienced architect & developer with a strong e-commerce background.
- Team building and leading experience.
- Highly experienced in building complex web applications from the ground-up, using best practices, the latest technologies and with scalability in mind.
- Self-taught, fast learner, solution-oriented.
- Excellent communicator with demonstrated organizational, leadership and mentoring abilities.

Contact Information

Katy, TX 281-799-1722 drew@johnston.us drew.johnston.us github.com/drewjoh linkedin.com/in/drewjoh

Skills

PHP / Javascript MySQL / Postgres
Git Team Building
HTML / CSS DevOps / Scaling
Caching Mulesoft
APIs Nginx
AWS / Cloud Technology Research

A/B Testing IT Consulting
Marketing Business Devel

Marketing Business Development

Education

Studied Computer Engineering Harding University 2001-2003

PayPal Certified Developer

Experience

2017 TO PRESENT Integration Architect Koch Business Solutions

- o Recruited by Koch for the newly created Integration Architect position.
- Became product owner for the Mulesoft Anypoint Platform for all of Koch Industries.
- Consulted with groups on new integration projects across all companies under Koch Industries, ensuring best practices and forward-thinking design with development strategies and implementations.

2016 το 2017 Senior Software Developer & Architect Appleton Talent / Spur Jobs

- Responsible for helping lead a team of 14 developers and designers to launch a new SaaS application.
- Given full responsibility over the architecting and implementation of all financial workflows.
- Responsible for providing direction to other developers, doing code reviews, mentoring, enforcing coding standards and developing architectural schemes.
- o Given Product Owner role over a subgroup of developers for feature specific development.
- Developed alternative deployment and application hosting strategies using new technologies, increasing performance by 200% at 1/3 the cost.
- On-call for DevOps related support.

2012 TO 2016 Software Architect & Senior Lead Developer Photojojo / Zoomin

- Fulfilled all development needs as the sole developer for 2.5 years.
- Solely responsible for interviewing, hiring, on-boarding, mentoring and supporting two developers.
- Planned, assigned and executed a complete rewrite of an 8-year-old legacy e-commerce system that would allow us to be flexible and grow into new business opportunities.
- Given full authority and responsibility for architecting and building the new system which included:
 - a front and backend for physical & electronic products with order management
 - multiple warehouse support
 - inventory management and tracking of all individual pieces
 - data analytics across all aspects of the business
 - scalable infrastructure, utilizing independent and grouped servers for different functions (admin, API, frontend, cron/worker)
 - multiple brand/website support utilizing a single backend/database
- Went from first Git commit to launch in 5 months; imported all legacy data.
- o Saved incredibly costly and rigid vendor lock-in with 3rd party hosted backend services.
- Managed the Houston, TX office that supported three developers.
- o Managed all DevOps related admin. (Servers, Email, DNS, CDN, Automated Deployments, etc.)
- Given responsibility and decision making authority for all development technology choices and related prioritization.

2001 TO PRESENT Owner / App Developer / IT Consultant Happy Cloud, LLC

- Created a custom e-commerce solution. Optimized shipping processes to bring the package & ship time per order from ~3 minutes to ~20 seconds. (2005 - 2006)
- Created a custom doctor/patient scheduling and video conference SaaS. Included a custom, secure (HIPPA compliant), embedded video conference software. Scalable to many doctor and clinics across the US. Helped the company land investors and launch. (2008)
- Created and continue to maintain a custom daycare management & invoicing web application for a high end day care chain in Houston, TX. (2011 - Present)
- o Continue to support all hardware & networking for a daycare chain in Houston, TX. (2006 Present)
- Various client website designs, integrations and projects.
- Server setup and administration for all projects.

2008 - 2012 Owner / Partner Coobo Media

- Responsible for all website coding and application development.
- Responsible for all server administration.
- Did business administration and finance.
- Created many custom web applications, from CMS's to online subscription services for digital products.
- Implemented a custom VoIP PBX solution for the office utilizing Asterisk; saved hundreds per month using a SIP Trunk instead of paying a phone company.

References

WILL OGLES Product Manager Spur Jobs

will@spurjobs.com

SUNNY RAO CEO Zoomin

o sunny@zoomin.com

AMIT GUPTA Original Owner Photojojo

me@amitgupta.com

KEVIN SISCO Software Developer / Business Partner / Personal Reference Shell Oil

kevin.sisco@gmail.com

EMILY COSNOTTI General Manager **Parabo Press** (sister company to Photojojo)

emilycosnotti@gmail.com

AUSTIN ANDREWS Developer Photojojo

o A5mercuryhu@gmail.com